I have 14 points that I'd like to start
with and I've not shared them with you
although we have been doing plenty of
talking about what's been transpiring
obviously I please tell me this is a
fourteen point plan to get us out of the
trouble it's it is not it is not but
there are there are fourteen points here
and I'm just I'm gonna share them and
then we'll talk about them okay all of
these things I believe to be true all of
them can be and I believe are true one
systemic racism has a long history
throughout the world and the legacy of
slavery in the u.s. is a particularly
salient example too in the u.s. we were
making progress against racism both at
the societal individual level we weren't
there we were not post race but we were
making progress the legacy of the civil
rights era meant that it was ever more
shameful and embarrassing to be publicly
racist and therefore more difficult to
be privately so as well we were making
progress into the last several years
when a perfect storm arrived just two of
the parts of that perfect storm are
these one by the early to mid 2010
everyone was carrying a camera in their
pocket in the form of smartphone video
footage of acts of police brutality
brought that violence to everyone's
living room there was now no denying it
the flip side of this is that the
visceral anecdote will always be more
powerful than the dispassionate
statistic so long as any grotesque
incidents exist and grotesque instance
will always exist so long as any exists
even if police and policing improved
dramatically
it will now be even more difficult to
point to the hopefulness of the second
truth and the second of many parts of
the second of the perfect storm which
have eroded the advances of the civil
rights movement are the ascendancy of
whoa culture and intersectional thinking
and critical theory they showed up first
in higher ed spread into schools of Ed
from there into k-12 schools into
cubicles journalism media the arts and
beyond this thinking holds among other
things that we have original sin based
on the color of our skin and that
there's no escaping it point three
blacklivesmatter point for the
organization that has come to be known
as black lives matter does not seem to
be the upstanding honorable organization
that its tagline would suggest five
emotion is high the reaction that George
Floyd's brutal and senseless killing was
and is emotional and that it's not
actually inherently a bad thing reason
and considered analysis are not the only
ways to communicate in the world showing
raw emotion is sharp and intense and
harsh and hard to look away from and
therefore it can be powerful when other
modes may not be working but sex the
months of lockdown which we have Brett
and I have and continue to argue were
and in some cases may continue to be
necessary for Public Health
made people less emotionally emotionally
resilient than they had been before and
more fragile furthermore I believe that
seeing people in so-called red states
party over Memorial Day weekend without
social distancing may have contributed
to the raw emotional outpouring by some
blue state protesters this is no
justification mind you just an
observation of factors contributing to
the mass protests that we are seeing
seven protest and the right to protest
are fundamental to democracy a riot is
not protest looting is not protest we
have no right to riot or to loot and
indeed rioting and looting or anathema
to democracy nine Trump is correct that
an tyfa is inciting violence and that
that violence is counterproductive to
having a peaceable society ten white
nationalists may also be involved in
inciting violence on American streets
right now and Trump has in the past
engaged in dog whistles to white
nationalists furthermore his explicit
mention Trump's explicit mention of the
Second Amendment in his mostly scripted
June first press conference can easily
be interpreted as a call to arms he said
quote I am mobilizing all available
federal resources civilian and military
to stop the rioting and looting to end
the destruction and arson and
the rights of law-abiding Americans
including your second Amendment rights
and quote
what is the Second Amendment doing in
that sentence in particular is it a call
to Civil War if this is what it is it is
beyond anti-patriotic it may even be
treason 11 some cops are racist thugs
some dentists are also racist thugs no
society should allow the racist thugs to
rise to positions of power racist thugs
who are policemen given their job are
able to do more damage to others than
our racist thugs who are dentists or
grocery clerks garbageman our
electricians point 12 most cops are not
racist thugs most cops like most
dentists and grocery clerks and garbage
men and electricians are honest people
with an interest in doing good thirteen
spreading blanket pronouncements of the
uniform evil of some demographic such as
with the acronym a cab all cops are
bastards or the or promoting the
inherent and unresolvable racism of all
white people is not just untrue but bad
for the cause that it is supposedly for
forced good and honest people to take
loyalty oaths or make an admission of a
mission of original sin where none
exists and some of those good and honest
people will become less good and less
honest others will wake up to the
hypocrisy at the core if a movement that
was supposed to do good and wonder where
to turn finally young Americans are in
debt their education have failed them
good health care is a distant memory the
prospect of owning a house is a pipe
dream for most many of them younger
among us were raised on legal
pharmaceuticals that have rendered us
psychologically disorganized unable to
track or control their own emotional
states or to read that of others and our
economy has become obsessed with making
us into consumers but consumption does
not provide meeting will find true
meaning in different ways some of us
will be driven to create some will be
driven to discover some will be driven
to heal others to communicate or to
build or to grow it is synthesised some
will find meaning in the protesting of
actual injustice in the writing of
wrongs there are so many sources of
meaning to be had
sted we are being controlled and
corralled sold to and lied to and
divided our humans deeply tribal and
competitive yeah our humans deeply
collaborative yes let us recognize our
shared humanity and celebrate our
individual differences we can do both we
can both recognize our shared humanity
and celebrate our individual differences
and the best leaders facilitate us doing
just that
Wow I have a great joke but I can't
deliver it because that was a very sober
and nuanced presentation so I'm going to
resist the urge to make light of it save
the joke no I'm saving the joke I will
fight I will if I have to organize a
podcast to justify that joke delivered
at the end as a punchline at some other
point I will do it but at the moment I
respond on mass or or go back to
individual points whether there's one
point in the interest of fairness and
clarity that I want to I don't want to
say correct because I think what you
said is technically right
but having tripped this wire last night
on Twitter I am sensitive to the hazard
it implies I have as yet seen very
little evidence of white nationalists
active at this moment in this protest I
have I have I have seen no evidence okay
but many and in fact the the the thing
that I left out here you know people are
saying is it antifa getting in the way
of legitimate protestors is it in doing
the rioting and looting and inciting
violence is it white nationalist is it
foreign countries right I know all of
these are out there as I bought the
season at some level the fact is its
divisive right so all I want to do is
make sure that we do not leave the
impression that there is evidence for
something for which we do not have
evidence so I've seen lots of stuff that
suggests there is
unnatural behavior I don't know if these
pallets of bricks that show up I had
another conversation with a business
owner today who's having trouble
sourcing bricks something odd might be
going on or not we don't know
but all I want to say is there is no
question in my mind that what is taking
place serves those very divisions and
may in fact lead to my biggest fear is
something like a race war that turns
into a civil war but as yet I have not
seen the misbehavior that I might expect
on the white nationalist side so make of
it what you will
[Music]